

Summary _

Software Engineer with around 4 years of experience specializing in fullstack web development. Interested in problem solving through code. Play guitar, bass and sing to keep myself creative, practice karate to keep myself healthy.

Skills_

Proficient JavaScript/TypeScript, HTML & CSS, Express, React, Redux, NodeJS, MongoDB, Webpack, Grunt, Gulp, Git

Knowledgeable Electron, Sass, Rust, Elixir, Phoenix, Ecto, PostgreSQL

Basic C, C++, Java, Lisp, Haskell, MFX, AWS, Docker, D3

Work Experience _____

ITN Networks New York City

FRONT END ENGINEER Jul. 2018 - PRESENT

- · Worked on various features on the company's front end codebase with over 1.5 million lines of code with 10 other engineers using React
- Integrated Cypress testing automation and developed a more reliable end to end testing infrastructure
- · Aggressively refactored the codebase to improve performance, readability and maintainability

IrisVR Inc.

New York City

SOFTWARE ENGINEER CONSULTANT Oct. 2016 - Mar. 2018

- Implemented build system on company's front end and desktop app development environment using Webpack
- Developed the company's front end client using React and Redux
- Developed the company's desktop client using Electron and React
- · Designed failure-point handling to handle disconnections between several NodeJS backend services gracefully
- Migrated company's MongoDB and AWS Redshift database changes with ensured consistency

FactorSpot Maryland

SOFTWARE ENGINEER CONSULTANT

VARIOUS CONTRACT DATES

Mar. 2015 - Dec. 2015

- Designed security policy over company's Firebase data
- Built a fullstack solution for the company using VueJS, Express and PostgreSQL
- Designed the company's SQL database model

CO-FOUNDER & SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Ninthbeat Inc.

New York City

• Built a marketplace platform for musicians to buy and sell their used musical instruments

- Utilized MEAN stack to develop a full-stack solution for the platform
- Develop a smartphone facing client using Ionic
- Integrated Firebase to be used as a real-time client chat feature

Education _

Queens College Flushing, NY

M.A. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (3.9 GPA) 2016 - 2018

Alliance Theological Seminary Manhattan, NY

M.Div. in Theological Studies 2010 - 2013

Bina Nusantara University

Jakarta, Indonesia

R Fig. in Industrial Engineering 2004 - 2008

JANUARY 27, 2019 CHRISTIAN SAKAI · RÉSUMÉ